Rahul Khairwar

Curriculum Vitae

A-101, Shah Heritage Sec-42/A, Seawoods(WEST) Navi Mumbai - 400706 ⑤ (+91) 8848385942 ⋈ rahulkhairwar@gmail.com

Profile

Computer Science Engineering graduate from National Institute of Technology, Calicut. Good knowledge of Data Structures and Algorithms through regular participation in competitive programming contests, since 2015.

Programming Achievements

ACM-ICPC Chennai Onsite Regionals 2016-17.

Attained 42nd rank.

Drishti'17 Dream Codex, NIT Calicut.

Attained 1st rank.

Tathva'16 Hackaholic, NIT Calicut.

Attained 2nd rank.

Others Online Competitive Programming Websites.

Codeforces, Highest Rating: 1732 (Expert)Codechef, Highest Rating: 2060 (5 Stars)

- Topcoder, Highest Rating: 1285

Work Experience

January Software Developer, ZILINGO, Bangalore.

2019-present

October Part-time Freelancer.

2018-present Small freelance projects in C/C++/Java

July 2017- Analyst, DEUTSCHE BANK, Pune.

December 2018

- Developed an automated script for updating multiple JSON files with data, which saved 2 hours of work every time new data has to be added.
- Worked with Java Servlet, JSP, AngularJS to build a web interface for displaying, filtering, and storing efficiently, data required for an internal DB product.
- Worked with Java and Apache Kafka's Java API for another internal DB product.

April 2016 - Android Developer for a Startup.

May 2016

- Created the complete user interface from scratch of an android application, for an Indian start up company Toud, based in Bangalore.
- Also used some open source solutions for image processing and caching like Picasso.

Projects and Developments

March 2017 - Intellij IDEA Plugin to automate testing for Codeforces Contests.

May 2017 Used Intellij IDEA API and Codeforces API to create a plugin for Intellij that automates the testing process of all sample tests for Codeforces contest questions.

Link to project: https://github.com/rahulkhairwar/cp-made-easy

December Automated Cricket Commentary for Whatsapp.

2018 Wrote a Python script to automatically fetch scores and commentary of a live match from ESPN Cricinfo, and send them to multiple Whatsapp contacts at regular intervals.

Link to project : https://github.com/rahulkhairwar/automated-whatsapp-cricket-commentary

October 2018 A Tennis Search Engine.

- November Built a simple search engine in a group of 3, that's for all things related to Tennis using

2018 Node.js, ReactJS, MongoDB(using mLab).

Link to project : https://github.com/rahulkhairwar/tennis-search-engine

October 2015 Restaurant Online Ordering Project in PHP.

- November Created the project using PHP and MySQL.

2015 Link to project: https://github.com/rahulkhairwar/Restaurant-Management

Education

2013–2017 National Institute of Technology, Calicut, Computer Science Engineering.

Technical Skills

Languages Java, Android, Node.js, C, C++, PHP, Python, Swift(Basic)

IDEs/Utilities Intellij, Android Studio, Visual Studio Code, Git

OS MacOS, Linux, Windows

Worked With SQL, MongoDB, JSON, XML

Certifications and Qualifications

Coursera Graph Search, Shortest Paths, and Data Structures, by Stanford University.

Certificate: https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/YJ83BGX8JBMA

Divide and Conquer, Sorting and Searching, and Randomized Algorithms,

by Stanford University.

Certificate: https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/4B93SPLQJSMB

SEED Advanced Java, Mumbai.

Infotech Android, Mumbai
Oracle SQL, Mumbai

Hobbies and Interests

- Charcoal Sketching. Some of my work:
 http://www.touchtalent.com/artist/289851/rahul-khairwar
- **Cooking**, Table Tennis, reading about new technology, listening to music.